-♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ Next Sunday, AD
♪ There was a guy named Joel
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked
at Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him, ♪
♪ so they shot him into space
♪♪
♪ We'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find
♪ La-la-la
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind
♪ La-la-la
♪ Now, keep in mind,
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La-la-la
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends
♪ Robot roll call
-Cambot!
-Pan left!
-Gypsy!
-Hi, girl!
-Tom Servo!
-What a cool guy!
-Cro-o-o-ow!
-He's a wisecracker.
-♪ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts --
la-la-la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself,
It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax
♪ For "Mystery Science
Theater 3000" ♪
♪♪
-♪ And the Blue
Ridge Mountains ♪
-Clay!
Clay!
I think I was spotted
on my way down here!
-Did you wear your disguise?
-I was wearing my disguise,
but I'm just not
very good in heels.
-No one must know
we're down here doing this.
-I'm sorry.
-Well, it's time to call Joel
about the experiment.
Come in,
Joely-Poely Puddin'-n-Pie!
-Hey, sirs, I'm ready for
this week's invention exchange.
Check this thing out.
I just made it.
It's the world's only
electric bagpipes, all right?
[Motor whirring,
bagpipes playing]
♪ Amazing grace
♪ How sweet the sound
Okay.
And, uh, the robots
and I have worked up
a special cover version of
Led Zeppelin's
"Whole Lotta Love."
You ready, guys?
-Ready!
-2, 3...
-Rock it!
-♪ She's gotta whole
lotta love ♪
♪ Wanna whole lotta love
♪ She's gotta whole
lotta love ♪
♪ A really whole lotta love
-I love it!
Look, Larry's corneas
are bleeding.
Oh.
Well!
It's time we sent you
our experimental nugget
this week, Joel.
Now, human underarm perspirationis something that happens
to everyone
after they go through puberty,
which, I assume,
includes you, Joel.
When's the last time
you saw a dog sweat?
Larry?
-Never!
-Exactly!
And why is that?
-Dogs don't sweat!
That's why!
-Exactly! Because of the dog's
pineal gland.
Nature's own
canine antiperspirant.
Now, you take the pineal gland,
and you make a serum.
You get a dog -- it doesn't
matter what kind of dog --
and you inject that serum
into a human subject --
in this case, Larry.
Now, let's see.
It's so hard to find a spot
I haven't hit.
Uh, what's this flower?
And who's Roseanne?
-Oh, just stick it, will you?
-Sail on, Silver Bird!
-D'oh!
Geez!
-Now, instantly, the serum racesthrough the bloodstream
like a Porsche Targa 911,
commandeering each pore,
slamming it shut,
like the vault at your favorite
savings and loan!
And, checking
the wetness sensors,
we see that they are free
from wetness and/or odor.
-Antidote.
-Oh! Yes, the antidote.
There you go.
The antidote.
And here is your treat.
-Oh, brother.
-That was pathetic!
-Eww!
-Hey, no, I thought
that was really good, you guys.
You're doing really well,
and I think that someday,
you'll be ready
for the Nobel Prize.
-Maybe for fiction!
-Hey!
Hey, I noticed you moved.
You guys must've got kicked out
of Gizmonic Institute
for shooting us
into space like this, I bet.
-Oh, don't be ridiculous!
We moved!
-It's our grand re-opening!
Uh, welcome to Deep 13!
-Deep 13?
Wait a minute!
That's in the sub-basement
of Gizmonic Institute!
I had to clean up
a flubber spill once there.
It's incredibly radioactive!
-But it hasn't affected
our brain any.
-We like it here!
Now we're even closer
to the atomic pile.
And one day...
-Well, I suppose it's time
for you guys to start
experimenting on us again.
-I'll tell you when it's time
to do the movie,
you squinty-eyed space chimp!
-Oh, uh, Clay?
-What?
-It is time.
-Oh.
Yeah, I --
-Nice insult, though.
-I knew that.
Thank you.
Well, it's a real stinkburger
of a film this week, Joel.
It's called "The Crawling Eye."
-Oh, it's got a bad audio track,it's in black-and-white,
and worst of all,
it stars Forrest Tucker.
-Hmm.
Good name, bad actor.
I'll put in the tape.
-[Laughing maniacally]
-Movie sign!
[Motors whirring]
[Wind howling]
-This must be
a Paramount picture.
Pardon me.
-Yep.
-Beautiful mountain.
-Hey, Jimmy!
-Hang on a minute!
Come see!
-Hey, Jimmy!
-Quit -- quit shouting!
-...you say?
-I tell you, it's foggy.
-It's a mountain.
It's supposed to be cold.
-That's bad Cary Grant
up there, isn't it?
-Who is it, Jim?
The abominable snowman?
-I tell you,
there's someone coming.
[Beeping]
-Funny.
-Oh, very good one.
-Who is it?
-Look!
No!
No-o-o-o!
-Going down.
-Gerald!
Help!
-Hey, let me help you there.
-Mountain flossing really
"rappels" me.
-Now pick it up.
-Heave!
Ho!
Heave!
-Can you see him?
-Not yet!
He's just below the lip.
-Oh, he got that hat
from Mike Nesmith.
-Here he is!
Jim!
No!
-Come on! Come on!
You idiot!
We nearly had him.
Why did you let him go?!
-Didn't you see him?!
-What are you talking about?
-His head!
It was torn off!
-You say that like
it's a bad thing.
[Eerie music playing]
-"The Crawling Eye."
Starring...
-Should be "The Crawling Knee."
-Oh, Forrest Tucker.
He's from "F Troop."
-Hey, Joel, how you supposed
to read these titles?
-Oh, well, Crow, it's simple.
You see the line up there?
-Uh-huh.
-That's -- See?
There's one there.
-Oh.
-Follow the line, and it shows
you right what to look at.
-"We are here."
-Yeah.
They quit doing it 'cause
people started figuring it out.
♪♪
-Kind of like titles
with idiot clips.
-Yeah.
♪♪
-Whoa.
-Duncan Sutherland.
Duncan.
What a yo-yo.
-Good one, Tom.
-Thank you so much.
-They're the men responsible.
♪♪
-Directed by us!
-Tempean.
-The light at the end
of the credits.
-Oh!
[Locomotive chugging]
-Let's see, Gemini, Gemini --
"You'll be attracted
to a crawling eye.
Leos figure prominently."
Hmm.
-Anne?
-Mm.
-Were you dreaming?
-Oh, I don't think so.
Why?
-You were talking in your sleep.
-I give away any secrets?
-Just that you're a man.
-Not really.
I didn't quite catch
his last name.
[Chuckles]
Would you like some tea?
-No, thank you.
-You sure you feel all right?
-What a babe.
-I feel wonderful.
I wish everybody would stop
treating me like an invalid.
-How about a wheelchair?
-Look, Anne,
there are the mountains.
-Hmm.
[Ominous music plays]
-"I am Mount Svengali.
You will do as I say."
♪♪
Whoa.
"Hey, my paper!
What the --"
-"Hey!
Dibs, dibs!
Everything on my lap I get!"
-What happened?
Did I -- Did I faint?
-Now, don't worry,
it's all right.
-Is there anything I can do?
-You're Sergeant O'Rourke
from "F Troop."
-Oh, uh, m-my name is
Alan Brooks.
-Oh.
Well, I'm Anne Pilgrim.
And this is my sister, Sarah.
-Hello.
-Billy.
-How do you do?
Uh...
There we are.
-That paper's shot.
-I'm sorry about your newspaper,
Mr. Brooks.
-Oh, that's all right.
I read the baseball scores.
There you are.
-It's just a prop, anyway.
-Shot of that'll bring
the color back.
-It's red dye number 7.
-Looks like you might do
with one.
-No, thanks.
-You have far to go?
-Geneva.
-Oh, it's a big convention town,
isn't it?
-Next, Trollenberg.
-Trollenberg?
-Yes, Trollenberg.
-Sarah, we're getting off
at Trollenberg.
-That's my stop.
-What's the matter, Anne?
You know we have
to go on to Geneva --
-No, I really can't go
any further today.
-We can stop
at the Hotel Europa.
-Hotel Europa?
We've never been to this place.
How do you know
about the Hotel Europa?
-I don't know.
-Anne, what's got into you?
-We're getting off
at Trollenberg.
Please, Sarah!
-"Don't argue with me."
"Trollenberg, home
of the crawling eye!
All stops lead
to a bloody death!"
-It's Mr. Haney!
-Oh, Herr Brooks.
Sorry I'm late.
Did you have a nice trip,
Herr Brooks?
-Herr Klein,
nice to see you again.
Oh, I'd like you to meet
Miss Anne and Sarah Pilgrim.
-"They'll drink anything."
-...the proprietor of
the Hotel Europa.
Wonder if maybe
you could help us out.
These young ladies have arrived
without any reservations,
but perhaps
you could put them up.
-Yes, uh...
Yes, it would be all right.
-Good.
-Thank you very much.
-The car's outside.
-Very good of you to put us up
at such short notice.
-Well, uh, this is not yet
our season, you understand?
-Oh, so now would've been
about your busiest time?
-Well, normally, yes, but, uh...
-"We've been having trouble
with the crawling eye."
-Is Hans still working for you?
-Yes, sir, Hans is still
working for us, Herr Brooks.
Thank you.
-Cigarette, Sarah?
-No, thank you.
-Hey, look, you guys -- they're
being followed by a movie.
-No, thank you.
-How about you, Herr Klein?
-Thank you, I don't smoke.
-They shouldn't have
started to climb.
-What are you talking about?
-An accident.
Last week, 1,200 feet
up the south col.
Three English students --
one of them was killed.
-Was there an accident,
Mr. Klein?
-On a mountain, uh...
These things sometimes happen.
-What else do you know
about the Trollenberg?
-Peasants are leaving
the mountain.
They say it's bad luck.
-The mountain people
are very simple.
They are superstitious.
Oh...
All these stories are nonsense.
-What stories?
-Nonsense stories.
-Disappearing into the mist
and never seen again.
-She isn't foreign.
-When in Switzerland,
visit Trollenberg.
-It's really picturesque.
♪♪
[Ominous music playing]
What a lovely matte painting.
♪♪
-Hans!
[Speaking German]
-[Imitating German]
"What's that supposed to mean?"
-Means, "The babes are coming."
-Oh.
-There they are.
-Ooh.
-Hello.
You must be Mr. Brooks.
Klein told us you were coming.
My name's Truscott,
Philip Truscott.
-How are you, Mr Truscott?
-Klein, you didn't tell us
we were expecting other guests.
-Oh, this is Miss Sarah Pilgrim
and Miss Anne Pilgrim.
-How do you do?
-"They'll drink anything."
-Sarah and Anne Pilgrim.
Swear we've met before.
The name rings a bell.
-Never been.
Would you mind if we went up
to our rooms now?
-"These aren't my clothes.
I don't look good
in stripes at all."
[Ominous music playing]
-She can eat corn on the cob
through a picket fence.
-It's all there.
The observatory at the foot
of the mountain.
The cable car.
There's a small hut
the climbers use.
You can see it
from the observatory.
It's all there, just like...
-Just like what, Anne?
-Well, just like...
♪♪
Sarah, why did I want
to come here?
What is there about this place?
Why do I feel
I've seen it all before?
-Don't worry about it, darling.
Lots of people
get a feeling like that.
Perhaps you read about it
in a book
or saw a picture
in a travel photo.
You mustn't let it affect you.
-No, I mustn't.
Yes, you're right.
I've probably read about it.
-In the script.
♪♪
[Theme music playing]
-Hi.
-How are you?
-Give you a hand?
-Well, I think I can manage.
-Lovely spot, this, isn't it?
-Certainly is.
-You've been here before,
haven't you?
-Yes, once, a couple years ago.
-Good climbing.
-So they tell me.
-Don't you climb?
-Not if I can help it.
-Must be his overnight gun.
-Odd place to come
for holiday...
if you don't climb.
-Hmm. Yes, isn't it.
-"Oh, this old thing?
Saved my life once."
-Taxing,
those two girls, aren't they?
-Certainly are.
-The Pilgrim sisters.
Sarah and Anne...
Of course I knew I'd seen them
before somewhere.
On the Palladium,
about a month ago.
They're a mind-reading act.
-Hmm.
-Funny they didn't say anything.
-Well, perhaps they, uh --
they wanted some privacy.
-"Just like me."
-And I'll buy you a drink later.
-All right.
-Good.
-He knows how to take a hint.
-He's kind of testy.
-Give me Zurich-6468, will you?
-"All right."
-Yes, I want you to check
on someone for me.
-Alan Brooks.
-"Alan Brooks?
Okay.
I'm checking on it."
-He's American.
He's about 40, I should think.
-"Was he on F Troop?"
-Why, you should
try New York first
and then Los Angeles
and then Washington.
-"All right."
-Okay.
-"Gotta go now."
-Right.
-Hello, there.
You'll be Brooks.
-"If you want me to."
-I'm Dewhurst.
This is Brett.
-"We're the Hat Brothers."
-How do you do?
-Looks like you're going
for a climb.
-Yes, we're going up
the Trollenberg.
Gonna have a noggin
before we start.
Care to join us?
-All right.
-What's it going to be?
-Scotch, please.
-Scotch and two brandies.
-Nothing like a little drinking
and climbing.
-Keep the cold out tonight.
-You, uh --
You're gonna stay the night?
-No, there's a hut at the foot
of the south col.
We'll sleep there
tonight and attack
the mountain proper tomorrow.
-"Unless it attacks us first."
-Hello, Truscott.
-"Who's the tomato?"
-You must be Miss Pilgrim?
-Yes, that's right.
-Oh, uh,
this is Mr. Dewhurst, Sarah.
And Mister...
-Brett.
-Brett, yes.
-How do you do?
-You care for a drink?
I appear to be in the chair.
Wish us bon voyage.
-Thank you.
I'll have a Campari.
-Truscott?
-Uh, scotch.
-Campari and another scotch,
Hans, please.
-Sit down, Sarah.
-Your sister's here with you,
isn't she?
Klein told us.
-Yes.
-Would she care to join us?
-No.
-Quite an occasion for me.
My first time up a mountain.
-Oh.
-Aren't you kind of fat
to be climbing a mountain?
-He's a big boy
in the Alpine Club.
-How did you come to
take up mountaineering?
-Wanted to see if we can't find
some good reason
for all these accidents.
I'm a geologist.
I know all about rock formations
and that sort of thing.
Well, here we are.
Cheers.
-Good luck.
-To a good climb.
-Keep an eye
on your roping, won't you?
-"Huh?"
[Ominous music plays]
-Why roping, particularly?
-"I don't know."
-...last week.
-That's right. Nasty business.
-Chill out.
-Very nasty.
-Nasty, nasty.
-What was that?
-Some kids, climbing
on the south col,
and one of them fell.
-They shouldn't have been
climbing without a guide.
-Or shoes.
-Seems he wasn't roped up
correctly,
and the rope got
caught up around his neck.
-Strangled him?
-Worse than that.
-"Killed him."
-Tore his head off.
-It was worse.
-"Then it strangled him."
-You don't know the half of it.
-"It was the fall
that killed him."
-Tell them what the villagers
say, Hans.
-It's not for me to...
-What do they say, Hans?
-"That's what they say --
'It's not for me.'"
-The guides who found him --
also his friends --
they swear the rope
was around his waist.
You understand,
it was still tied.
-Well, but how could
it have, uh...?
-The villagers have something
to say about that, too.
Haven't they, Hans?
-It was a trick knot.
-Excuse me.
♪♪
-What do the villagers
say, Truscott?
-"They say, 'It's not for me.'"
-They say it happened
before he fell.
-They all say that.
-As I said,
they shouldn't allow
inexperienced climbers
up the Trollenberg
without a guide.
There are bound to be accidents.
-Yes, you watch your roping.
-We ought to get moving
if you want to make
the hut before nightfall.
-"We've got a death scene
to make."
-Oh, uh, I'm going up
to the observatory.
I'll hitch a ride with you
in the cable car.
That is, unless you're gonna
climb the whole way.
-Climb the whole way?
Not if I can help it.
♪♪
-See, when an important
chemical changes,
it can take place inside rock,
which cause a physical
alteration
to its structure.
In time, it could be come
like chalk --
break away in your hand.
-What do you think
of that, Brett?
-Hmm?
No, I don't think
it's like that.
A mountain's a mountain.
Some people can climb it,
and some can't.
-Some people can speak dialogue,some can't.
-Those that can't
shouldn't try.
-I'm here under sufferance.
-How long do you think
it'll take you to reach the hut
from the observatory?
-I don't know.
-Oh, about 3 1/2 hours.
An easy climb.
-"That's good.
I'm wearing a sport coat."
♪♪
Meanwhile, in the observatory...
-Professor.
Professor.
-How many more times do I tellyou, I am not to be interrupted.
-I'm sorry, sir, but there's
someone outside to see you.
-I don't care.
Tell them to go away.
-He says his name is Brooks.
-Tell him to --
-"Huh?"
-Alan Brooks?
-Yes, sir.
-Well, bring him in,
bring him in!
Now, wait, wait!
I'll bring him in myself.
-"No, wait, wait.
You get him.
No, I'll get him.
Uh, yeah, I'll get him.
I have to do
everything around here."
-Alan.
My dear Alan!
Ha ha!
They all get that for leaving
you out here!
Come in, come in.
Ah, it's good of you to come
and see me,
and on your holidays, too.
I was lucky you were in Europe.
You got my letter?
-Yes.
-Well, you don't say very much.
What's the matter?
You're not pleased to see
your old friend?
-Wie geht, Herr Professor?
-And how are you, Alan?
Come in, come in!
-What a goof.
Well, Alan, what do you think
of our little observatory, eh?
-Groovy pad.
-You know, the government gives
me as much money as I want.
-Very retro.
Needs some more color, though.
-I'll show you something.
-Television?
-Better than windows.
So, look.
-Look --
the all-weather channel.
These are mountains you won't
see on any other station.
-You see?
Television cameras on the roof.
We watch everywhere.
[Chuckles]
You know, the government --
the government, they say to me,
"Professor, do you have to have
such expensive things?
Windows are much cheaper."
And I say, "I have to have,"
and I have!
-Do you think that's funny?
-That over there,
that is the only window.
-Science humor.
-And even from that,
we have protection.
Look.
-"Now the windows
are even smaller.
But I can make them big again."
-Could just get roller blinds.
-That will stand up
to any avalanche.
[Chuckles]
But that, too, was very
expensive.
All this to study cosmic rays.
Well, Alan, come
into my office, huh?
Well, Alan, here we are.
Same old mess, huh?
-"But it's an expensive mess."
-Well, you're looking very fit.
-Well, I look
the same as always.
Come on, quit your stalling,
Professor.
You forget I know you.
You said in your letter that
I should see you right away.
What's so urgent?
-How long have you been here
in Trollenberg, Alan?
-Got here this morning,
came right up to see you.
-"So you haven't tried
the fish yet."
-You haven't heard about
the accidents, then?
-Yes, I heard
about the students.
-Yeah, that was one of them,
but...
But there's been others --
many others.
-Where people climb mountains,
there are lots of accidents.
-That's true.
And sometimes, the bodies,
they disappear.
But here, the search parties
go out,
and always they find nothing.
Now, why is that?
-They're not good
search parties?
-But they're expensive.
-I don't know.
-And then, there is the cloud.
-What cloud?
-Come on, Alan, you know
what I'm talking about --
the cloud
where there should be no cloud.
-"Oh, yeah, oh,
yeah, that cloud."
-Where there are mountains,
there are always clouds.
-But this one remains static
on the side of the Trollenberg.
It never moves.
-Oh, right.
-A freak of nature.
-Hey.
-A radioactive freak of nature?
-Radioactive?
-Mm-hmm.
-Can we see it from here?
-Come.
I'll show you.
[Motors whirring]
-Okay. What did you guys think
of the movie so far?
-Well, I thought
there'd be more music.
You know, more of
a Julie Andrews quality.
Ow.
-Julie Andrews quality?
Isn't that a contradiction
in terms?
-Now, come on, Crow.
What did you think
of the movie so far?
-Well, Joel, I can't understand
why everybody's so upset
about losing their heads.
What's so bad about that?
I've seen Servo's head
on the workbench lots of times.
-Yeah, screws right off.
It's a pop top.
-Ew.
-Well, listen,
it's not like that.
It's really --
Human beings are made
completely different, you guys.
Once our heads are separated
from our bodies,
that's pretty much
the end of the show for us.
It's just the way we're made.
-Can't you use your backup
copy and reboot?
-Uh, no.
Nope, nothing like that.
-Well, then why do people say
that they're always like,
"I'd lose my head
if it wasn't screwed on"?
-Yeah, and people often say
their heads
aren't in the right places.
-Yeah, and, Joel, once I heard
the scientists talking,
and they said you had
your head up your a--
-Uh, well, Crow, that was just
a figure of speech, all right?
-Figure of speech?
Now, what's that
supposed to mean?
-Oh, like the body
of a paragraph, perhaps?
-I think that's
a literary figure.
-Oh, maybe like
Edna St. Vincent Millay?
-Now there's a body!
-Now listen, you guys,
I'm trying to
teach you something, all right?
-Joel, what about head games?
-And head trips?
-And how do you
explain head cheese?
-Well, uh, head cheese --
I don't explain head cheese.
But, uh, here are
some people who do.
♪♪
-Joel, will you carry me
everywhere from now on?
-I gotta put wheels
on you sometime.
-Hey, look! It's that painting
we saw earlier.
-Alan, come here.
-"Hey, wait for me.
Hey!"
-"Keep up."
-Now, you see, here --
here's a map of the area.
-"Admittedly,
it's not a very good map."
-The Trollenberg.
-Yep, that's Trollenberg.
-That is the scan
atop of the roof here.
And you see, at the moment,
nothing.
No reaction, nothing.
Now, remember,
here is the cloud.
I turn on the scanner.
So, now watch
when it passes the cloud.
-Where's the cloud?
Where's the cloud again?
-Now, you see,
it passes the cloud, nothing.
Watch it go 'round again.
-Where's the cloud?
Where is it? Ah.
[Sputtering]
-It's a cloud of baked beans,
I think.
-Sounds like it, right, Tom?
-Sure does.
-Well, what do you
think of that?
Now, Alan, I ask you to think
back three years ago,
to what happened in the Andes.
-Well --
Well, this can't be the same.
-Why not?
They have accidents like before,we have the cloud like before.
Why can't it be the same?
-There's too many
things missing.
-Like a plot.
-Mental compulsion.
-What is it?
-This girl on the train.
She --
She suddenly decided she had
to get off at Trollenberg.
She was booked for Geneva.
But she had to get off
at Trollenberg.
-And did she?
-Yes.
-She had to.
-She's at the hotel.
-There's climbers
on the Trollenberg.
-Climbers?
I thought they were
all scared away.
Where are they?
-60 degrees west of due north.
-Hey, it's "F Troop."
-[Whistling]
-2,000 meters.
-Two guys.
Hey.
-Captain Parmenter.
-It's Brett and Dewhurst.
-"Isn't he too fat to be
climbing a mountain?"
-You know them?
-Well, just from the hotel.
They came up with me
on the cable car.
-Well, they should be all right
as long as they stick
to their present track.
-And they keep their heads
on their necks.
-The cloud is well
to the west of the pass.
-Mm.
-Alan...
will you do something
about what I told you?
-The cloud?
-Mm.
-Do what?
-Inform the authorities.
-Look, I'm on a holiday.
Besides, you haven't told me
anything that can be proved.
-I've told you about the cloud,
I've told you
about the accidents.
What more do you want?
-Facts, proof.
-Scotch.
-Something that'll look real
in black-and-white
on somebody's desk.
I don't know.
Not gonna stick my neck
out again
like I did in the Andes.
-But why?
You were employed
by the United Nations.
It was all in the report.
-Look, by the time the Andes
report was in,
there wasn't anything left
in the area,
explained or otherwise.
They practically accused me
of dreaming the whole thing up.
So if I was to take a hand here,
I'd have to have a list
of documented facts.
They'd have to be
pretty conclusive.
-"Or I'll look like
a dork again."
-You're an important man.
Why don't you
get through to Bern?
-"Important."
I'm only important if I say
something about cosmic rays.
If I say anything else, theytell me to mind my own business.
-Why don't they give him
something to study
that he can pronounce?
-Maybe you should
speak to Klein.
-Hotel proprietor?
-Well, he's also the mayor
of Trollenberg.
Perhaps he could help.
Anyway, he could supply
a list of the accidents.
-He might be more interesting.
-Then perhaps you do
something yourself.
-Oh.
[Wind howling]
-Meanwhile, back
at Daniel Boone's house...
-"Damn. I'm just too fat to be
climbing a mountain."
[Joel chuckles]
-"What a nice place."
-"Gee, there's only one bed.
Guess we'll have
to flip for it."
-He's too fat to flip.
-"Hmm, let me see.
I could kill the fat guy
with this.
Nope, too flimsy.
Yeah, this is it!
Nice and hefty."
-You all right?
All right,
take your pack off, man.
You can't relax like that.
I'll call Weight Watchers.
[Ringing]
-Hello?
Yes, Herr Brett.
You arrived all right?
-"Uh-huh."
-Good.
Good.
A nice sleep will set you right.
-Yes, all right.
-"Okay."
-Goodbye.
-"Thanks a lot, bye."
-It was Herr Brett.
They have arrived at the hut.
You see?
There's nothing to worry about.
It's just unfortunate
that this year we have had
many inexperienced climbers.
-And what about the rumors
in the village?
-Well, you know these people,
Professor.
They are superstitious.
They like to believe
in fairy stories.
Gentlemen, you understand.
Officially,
there's nothing I can do.
-"Except sit here
and drink heavily."
-"Dear Diary, once again
the fat guy got the bed."
-...back tomorrow,
if we travel light.
-I must have a sack
for rock samples.
-Well, I think
we can manage that.
You can take your sack.
♪♪
-"Penny for your thoughts.
Think we'll ever get married?"
-Visibility's not too good.
Hope it'll clear.
-Fog?
Out here?
-"Oh, it's just a painting.
Sorry.
My mistake."
-Moving down from the peak.
-Will this do, Miss Pilgrim?
-Oh, this will be fine.
Quite a collection
you have there.
Now, would somebody
bring Anne in, please?
-Oh, yes.
-Do we have to?
-Now, you see that I make
no signals to Anne
and say nothing.
-Anne?
-So it's impossible
for any sort of code to be used.
[Clearing throat loudly]
-The bank note is French.
-"It's a mango."
-500 francs.
-"Mm-hmm, mm-hmm."
-There's a number on it.
-H...
0...
1...
8...
8.
-Well done.
-And who does it belong to,
young lady?
-[Coughing] "Roberts!
Roberts!"
-"Pretty good."
-It's a rounded sort of object
about the size of a tennis ball.
-"Paperweight, paperweight."
-Made of glass.
I think it's used
as a paperweight.
-"Good, good."
-There's a model inside it.
A mountain and a little hut.
And when you shake it,
there's a snowstorm.
-"When you shake it,
the heads come off."
-"Rosebud."
[Chatter]
-No.
Mountain...
hut...
Two men in the hut.
-Anne!
-"The fat one takes the bed."
-There's the fat one.
He's asleep.
-"In the bed."
-But he is not the one.
The other one...
looking at the table.
-"Dreaming...
doubting."
-"Writing in his diary."
-He's the one.
[Ominous music playing]
Getting up.
Coming towards the door.
-Maybe she's not psychic.
Maybe she's controlling him.
If she shuts up,
maybe he'll sit down.
-He's opening it.
He's coming out.
Up the slope.
-Flash!
Mr. and Mrs. America
and all ships at sea!
This is a banner extra,
front-page stuff!
"Girl has vision!"
-Mountain...
Paperweight.
Glass paperweight.
-"Dude, she's mine.
I'll get her arm."
[Telephone ringing]
-Hello?
-Hello, Brett?
-Dewhurst here.
What do you want?
-Are you all right?
-Yes.
Why?
-Is Brett there?
-Of course he is.
Wouldn't go wandering off
in the middle of the night.
-"Hmm?"
-Wait, hold on.
-"Now I'm fat and awake.
Who keeps calling me?
Thanks for calling me, jerk."
-Dewhurst!
Dewhurst, is Brett there?
Can you hear me?
Dewhurst!
Are you there?
Hello, hello?!
-"Now I have to walk
back over here."
-Hello?
-"Could you order me a pizza?"
-You're right.
He's not here.
He must've just gone out.
I better go look for him.
-No, don't do that.
You'll be lost in 5 seconds.
Just sit tight where you are.
-I think I should go.
There may be something wrong.
-No, you're not to move.
Stay in the hut!
What's the weather like?
-Not very good.
Some heavy cloud coming down.
-Well, then stay where you are.
There'll be somebody at this endof the phone all night.
If Brett shows up or if youneed us, ring us here, will you?
-All right.
Bye.
-Bye.
-"Well, let's see.
Something to hold me over."
[Humming]
"Ah, can't eat that
or it'll just make me hungrier.
Maybe the blanket."
-Brett?!
Brett?!
-"Echo!"
-"It was a bizarre dream.
And you were all there."
-Why? What happened?
-"Fanny Flag and Groucho
and Carl Sagan,
and it was
a Dick Cavett PBS special."
-Well, we need something
to relax your sister.
A sedative perhaps.
You have such a thing?
-I may have some sleeping pills
in my room.
Shall I see if I can find them?
-Oh, please, thank you.
Sarah, could I speak with you
for a minute, please?
-All right.
[High-pitched whine]
I shan't be a minute.
-What's that noise?
-It's like someone sharpening
a pencil or something.
-I think it's
the electric blanket.
-Oh, Miss Sarah, I don't
want you to upset yourself.
-Are these any good?
-He prescribed those for Elvis.
-Yes, it's fine.
Now, you give her two of these,
then come downstairs.
Please hurry.
-All right.
-"Is it my breath?"
[Theme music playing]
[Telephone ringing]
-Hello?
-"My pizza ready?
It's been over a half-hour."
-It's foggy as hell outside.
You know I can't see far.
Perishing cold, too.
Yes. Yes.
Hold on a minute.
There's someone outside.
Hang on.
-Maybe it's the neighbor kids.
-Could be the pizza man.
-"Man, get out of my flowers."
-It's the stealth pizza man.
-Brett?
Brett, is that you?
♪♪
False alarm, I guess.
Hang on a minute.I've just got to close the door.
♪♪
Aah!
-It's the Noid.
-Do we ever get to see
the monster, Joel?
-Dewhurst!
Can you hear me?
Dewhurst!
Dewhurst?!
Hello, hello?!
Dewhurst!
[Dewhurst screaming]
-"Anchovies."
-Well?
-"He said anchovies."
-Phone's gone dead.
[Telephone ringing]
-That one hasn't.
-Hello?
Yes, speaking.
Yes.
-It's Harpo.
-I see.
-"Hmm?"
-All right.
All right.
-He said anchovies.
-It was the observatory.
The cloud has moved away
from the hut.
Back up the Trollenberg.
[Bell ringing]
-Oh, nice reel change.
[Speaking German]
-"You think this outfit
is too busy?"
-We'd better start now.
It will be light soon.
-Herr Klein.
-Ja.
-I thought the locals
were afraid
of going up that mountain.
-They are afraid.
There's an unwritten law here.
Time like this, they --
they go up, no matter what.
-Even without pants.
-I have called a spotter plane.
But it will not be up
till morning.
We will be well
on our way by then.
Ready?
-All right, Herr Klein.
-Good.
-"Should I have my glasses
on or off for this climb?"
-Look after yourself, Alan.
-Don't worry.
I'll stop by the observatory
on the way down.
-Good.
Be careful, everybody.
-"Don't lose your heads."
-"These four brave men --"
-"Aah!"
-"...three brave men --"
-"Uh, two brave men, soon to go
down in the annals of history."
-"Look at that staircase.
Would you look
at the staircase?"
-"Wow.
What a staircase."
-"Man, what a staircase.
Boy, I'm getting winded.
How about you, Forrest?"
"Oh, yeah."
-"Hey, quit bunching up."
-"What's that?"
-"Got enough left
for this staircase."
-"Whoa."
-"Watch your step."
-Why did they bring
so much licorice?
[Groaning]
-Hey, she's chasing rabbits
in her sleep.
-Here they come.
-Professor.
-"Thumper, Fluffy, Bugs."
-"Rico, Youngblood."
-He's climbing the ledge.
He'll be here soon.
Remember the hut.
Keep him away.
Keep him away from the hut!
Away from the hut.
-And Starsky.
-Hut, hut, hut 1, hut 2.
Poor kooky kid.
-Maybe she shouldn't
sleep so much.
-Professor, what's the matter?
Why does she behave like this?
-She's a method actor.
-Well...
Well, it's like
a radio receiver.
You see, your sister's mind
is capable of receiving signals
sent out by other minds.
By yours, for example.
-"Let's start
with a simple test.
Can you tell where
I'm looking right now?"
-Now there is a stronger signal,I think.
A stronger mind.
It's jamming the wavelength.
-"Is she AM or FM?"
-But who is it?
-Well, we shall know more
about that, I think,
when they reach the hut.
In the meantime,
I say to you again,
get your sister out of here
before it is too late.
-Too late for what?
-"Last call? Take-out?
Too late for heroes?
Tell me!"
-Well, it's time I was getting
back to the observatory.
-Too late for what, Professor?
-"Last call?
Tell me!
You're keeping this from me."
-When they reach the hut,
then we
will know for sure, I think.
-"Ah."
[Knocking]
-The door's locked
from the inside.
They must be in there.
Mr. Brett!
Mr. Dewhurst!
-Had a look in
through the window.
The place seems deserted.
[Banging]
-"Hey, a doorknob.
Can I keep it?"
-Philip, come here.
-"Oh!
Ow."
-These blankets -- frozen stiff.
-"Must've slept with his hand
in lukewarm water."
-Where are they?
-That door was barred
on the inside.
-Yeah.
-Herr Brooks!
-Pants, with the leg
still in them.
-Those are the best kind.
-"Careful not to pull too hard.
His head might be caught
on something."
-"He's huge!"
-Dewhurst...
His head's been torn off.
-"Ripped off."
-Anne, we're leaving here today.
-No, Sarah.
Why not? Look, after last night,surely --
-I just want to stay here.
That's all.
-"We haven't tried
the fish yet."
-Now, Anne, I really mean this.
We're leaving Trollenberg today.
All right?
-"You're thinking of a color.
There's someone
in the room named Bob."
-Shut up.
-"Two superpowers will unite
to fight a third."
-Stop it!
-"Two brothers will reach
the Senate.
One will become President.
Both will die."
-Shh!
Hush.
♪♪
-"Can I have that toast?
Are you gonna eat that toast?"
♪♪
[Beeping]
-The matte painting
is calling you.
Go to the window.
[Beeping]
♪♪
-Go to the closet.
Unpack your clothes.
Open your suitcase.
Take out a foundation garment.
Cut to another scene.
-Keep it hid.
-"You guys take the torso."
-Joel, carry me, will you?
-I'm getting outta here.
-Herr Brett is
an experienced climber,
so we can only assume
that he's hurt.
We all better search.
The little spotter plane
could be here any minute.
[Theme music playing]
-He's not gonna like this.
-And I'm not gonna tell him.
You tell him.
-Well, maybe he won't notice.
-Oh, yeah, right.
Hey, Cambot, could you speed
this up a little bit?
-Uh-oh.
-Oh.
He's here.
Oh.
-Uh, Joel, I don't to be
a teacher's pet or anything,
but Gypsy
uncoiled herself again!
-Yeah, she did.
Cambot, could you widen it out
so everybody can see this?
Gypsy, I know you're in here!
Quit hiding!
You clown, get out here!
Oh.
Oh, let's do that thing
we did, okay?
-All right.
-It's too bad Gypsy's not here,
huh, Crow and Servo?
-Yeah.
-It's too bad she's gonna
miss out
on those piping-hot RAM chips.
-Mm-hmm.
-RAM chips?
-Oh, all right.
I knew you were around here
somewhere.
Listen, you know you're not
supposed to come out
without using
the service portal.
Now, look,
I want to show you this.
See this big mess you got?
[Gypsy wailing]
All over the place.
That's --
-Put it back! Put it back!
-Hey, this is --
this is how you look, okay?
Now, otherwise, we're gonna haveexoservo spinal bundle
all over the place.
-What?
-The black stuff.
-Oh.
Hey, Joel?
-What's that?
-I got an itch.
-Oh, terrific.
She's got an itch.
Okay.
-Happy day.
-Okay.
Where is it, Gypsy?
-Vertebrae 6805 through 7219.
-Vertebrae 6905 through 7018.
Okay, you guys,
start scratching.
Where's my rake?
-Whoa!
-I hate it
when she gets diode rash.
-Me too.
Uh, Tom Servo, I think
you're scratching on
the solar collector cable.
-Oh, right.
-So am I.
Wait a minute now, here.
-Why am I doing this?
I hate being the end man.
I scratch her,
and it takes her six hours
to feel it in her head.
-Uh, Joel, uh, I don't want
to ask a stupid question,
but why'd you make her so big?
-Well, you know how --
It's kind of like when you startconnecting paper clips together.
You get hooked on it.
It's kind of like that.
-Oh, my.
-What's that, Tom?
-Joel, you remember when we
were speculating on her sex?
-Yeah.
-Well, I think I may
have narrowed it down here.
-Oh, yeah?
-Uh...
Oh. Oh. Check that.
Sorry.
False alarm.
-Here's the --
I think I found the problem.
She's jammed in here
behind the door.
-Hey, don't open
that door, McGee!
-Happens every time.
We got movie sign!
[Motors whirring]
-I feel safe in your arms, Joel.
-Plane to party.
Plane to party.
Are you receiving me?
-"Party here.
Pick up some ice
and some cubes."
-Party to plane --
receiving you loud and clear.
-"Get some paper cups."
-What is your position?
-Our position -- map reference,
265-843, over.
-"Can't miss it.
Dave's van's parked
right out in front."
[Engine droning]
-Vroom!
-Roger, party.
I can see you now.
I shall fly north for 5 miles...
-For no apparent reason."
-...then further west
for 5 miles,
then south.
-Uh-huh.
-Then you'll be back
in the exact same spot.
-Roger, plane.
[Airplane engine droning]
-I --
-"What the...?"
-She didn't make her bed again.
-She's...
This is her nightgown.
-She's not in there.
-"She's been digging
through my stuff."
-"Let's see.
She went to the closet.
Hey, she took my stuff.
Then she must've gone
to the window."
♪♪
-I didn't know they had cable.
-♪ The hills are alive,
and it's getting scary ♪
♪ That cloud over there
wasn't there before ♪
-Hello?
-Hello.
-I want to speak
with the observatory.
Professor Crevett.
-"De plane!
De plane!"
-"Don't crash, don't crash,
don't crash.
If I concentrate,
I won't crash."
-"Let's see.
Let's find a flat spot here."
-"Whoa!
Here's the party!"
-Hello, party.
This is the plane.
I've spotted him.
He's approximately half a mile
due north of your position,
above the north face.
-Roger, plane.
-Big part for him.
-Look out for the mountain!
[Imitates explosion]
♪♪
-"Hi. I'm the curator
of the matte painting."
-Miss Pilgrim, my name's Wilde.
Professor Crevett sent meto bring you to the observatory.
-But I'm not to go
to the observatory.
-Well, there's nowhere else
to go out here.
And it's only
a couple hundred yards.
-I'm to go up the mountain.
-I don't think so, Miss Pilgrim.
I think you ought to wait
a while at the observatory.
-"What color is the sky
in your world?"
-"Just about.
Almost, almost."
[Grunting]
[Speaking German]
-"What?!"
-He said, "Here's a bloody bag."
♪♪
Better have a look-see.
[Echoing]
-Herr Brett!
-Echo!
-"Need to shave."
-"Oh.
Pudding?"
-Maybe it's somebody's lunch.
-Hey, kommen sie hier!
Schnell!
-"Kommen sie hier, schnell"?
-"Alright?
S'alright."
-"We found Hoffman."
"You looked in my bag!"
-Hey, buddy, it won't get betterif you pick at it.
-"Uh, yeah, your friend, I got
a bone to pick with you, too."
-I suppose you want to look
in my bag, too!"
-"And it's yours."
That's gotta hurt.
-Thirty degrees west.
[Whirring]
How about that?
-Negative.
-Hubert?
-Swing another 30 degrees.
[Whirring]
-Negative.
-Everybody's so negative.
-Try the other circuit.
Oh, wait.
Switch back to the first circuit
and reverse this time.
Now.
-This will never replace
Nintendo.
-"Now's my chance to beat it."
-"Hope I don't run into
Forrest Tucker.
Oh!"
-Oh, hello, Anne.
What are you doing up here?
-"Uh, nothing."
-Probably waiting
for the commercial.
-Go?
Go where?
-The Trollenberg --
I must go now.
-Don't let her go.
-Don't worry.
Come along, Anne.
-Oh, good.
Alan, I want to speak with you.
-Yeah, I got news for you, too.
Hans, when's the next cable car
go down the mountain?
-It shouldn't be long, sir.
-Good, I --
I want you to take Anne down.
Don't let her out of your sight.
Anne, I want you
to go with Hans.
-"He's a warm and wonderful man.
You'll be very happy."
-Roping Hans.
-"Hey, everybody, I got a girl."
"They make a lovely couple,
don't they?"
-Well, I've been to the hut.
-And?
-Dewhurst is dead.
Brett's missing.
-[Sighs]
Not that I'm surprised,
mind you.
The cloud has
started moving again.
-Ah.
-What cloud.
-Bozo the cloud.
-I don't think you'd understand,Philip.
-"You're much too stupid."
-Like that time in the Andes,
you mean?
-"Hmm?"
-How do you know about that?
-"I get around."
-All right.
I'm a newspaperman.
It's my job to know
about these things.
-"Oh!"
-I see.
-I chased that story when we gotwind of your report, Alan.
When I got there,
it was too late.
Look as if I'm gonna be more
fortunate this time, isn't it?
-Yeah, fine, fine.
That's --
That's just what we need.
-Haven't answered my question,
Professor.
-What question?
-Is this the same
as it was then?
-"Well, that was then,
and this is now."
-So, what happens now?
-"This."
-The United Nations had
a special team
investigating phenomena.
I call them in.
-"They also double as
our softball team."
-Does the theory that you put
forward last time
still hold, Professor?
-What theory?
-Visitors from outer space.
That was it, wasn't it?
-And what else?
-Well, what are they?
What do they want?
-Look, Philip...
-The fish.
-...there are many galaxies
besides ours.
Now, who knows what is happeningmillions of miles out in space?
-Sagan knows.
-Perhaps the world
that these creatures
inhabit is coming to an end.
Perhaps they need to find
somewhere else to live.
-Well, why pick on us?
-We don't know it's just us.
Maybe it's also Mars, Venus,
Jupiter.
Who can tell?
-Do you go along with this?
-Well, until somebody comes up
with a better theory...
-Or a sitcom.
-...yes, yes, I do.
-All right.
All right.
While we're theorizing, why doyou think, do they always happen
to land
on the top of a mountain?
First, the Andes,
and now the Trollenberg.
-Well, it's the atmosphere,
I think.
You see, it gets
much thinner high up.
Perhaps these
creatures need that.
The cloud would seem
to indicate this, too
Creating their own atmosphere.
-Well, if they can only exist
on the tops of mountains,
they're hardly likely to inheritthe Earth, are they?
-You see, anyone can get used
to anything in time.
-"Like I you."
-Now, these movements we have
recorded here,
each time,
lower down the mountain.
The climitization effect.
-What next, Professor?
-The next move
is up to you, Alan.
You must inform the authorities.
-Or the authorities.
-Have you seen the professor?
-He's in the office
with Alan Brooks.
They're telephoning Zurich.
-Any sign of Mr. Brett yet?
-Well, the plane spotted
someone he thought was him,
and two of the searchers
went to meet him.
The others are back.
They saw nothing.
-Well, if it was Brett,
they ought to be back by now.
-Where's your sister?
-She's in her room.
-Good.
-You think she's safe
from our friends up there?
-Well, I don't think they'll
try the same thing again.
Trouble is, what will they try?
[Imitating theme from "The Good,the Bad and the Ugly"]
-You all right?!
-Wow.
He looks dead on his feet.
-A bit tired.
Otherwise, all right.
-Where have you been?!
We've had search parties
out for you!
-I was lost.
-In a fog, if you will.
-When did you see him last?
-Dewhurst?
-Yes.
-Well, last night I saw him.
-At the hut.
-Yes, at the hut.
It's a bit hot in here.
Pour me a drink, Klein.
-Have one on me.
-Let me help you.
-Sorry.
Thank you.
-He can't handle his liquor.
-How's your sister,
Miss Pilgrim?
-She's all right, now.
-Where is she?
-She's in --
-Here.
Have a cigarette.
-Great.
We saw how well he did
with the booze.
Now let's give him
something that's lit.
-[Imitating Raymond Babbitt]
"429 matches exactly.
Exactly 429."
-That's a good
impression, Servo.
-"I'm an excellent driver."
He's gonna light his nose!
Look out!
-What're they gonna have him
do next?
Have him drive
a forklift you guys?
Gee.
Glutton for punishing others.
-"Let's get the dog drunk next."
-It's too scary up there
on your own.
-Were you out on your own?
-After I lost Dewhurst.
-I'm sorry to be a nuisance,
but may I --
[Ominous music plays]
-Then she walked in.
♪♪
Ooh!
-He's kind of pigheaded.
-Oh, that smarts.
-Look at his head.
-At least he's got one.
-But...
there's no blood.
-"He's wearing
Mr Spock's jammies."
-Dig a little deeper.
-Yeah, that's a good idea --
solder him back together.
-There.
That should take care of him
till the morning, I think.
-Good.
-He should be up
and spilling liquor in no time.
-Dr. Becker can have
a look at him.
-Do we tell the others
what he was trying to do?
-I don't know.
-Hmm.
Looks great.
-"Let's lock him in here."
-I don't know about you,
but I could use a drink.
-So what else is new?
I think we all
could use a drink.
[Theme music playing]
♪♪
-"Who put this zipper
in my head?
♪♪
Wow.
What a party.
I'm dead tired.
Little thirsty, though.
I need a drink.
Maybe some formaldehyde.
Hope they serve the dead here."
♪♪
-Looks like Popeye.
-[Mimics Popeye's laughter]
"Oh.
Somebody's comin'
down the hallways."
-"Huh. Doesn't look like
anybody's in there.
Well, I'll see about that.
Huh."
-"Yeah, I think I'll reach
through and get hims."
-"Hey, Popeye!
Ooh!"
♪ I'm Popeye the sailor man
♪ I've got a guy's head
in my hand ♪
-That's a legal submission hold.
-Sounds like a bad Popeye
impression to me.
♪♪
-I think you've
proved your point.
-Dropped him like a bad habit.
-He's just misunderstood.
-Most dead people are.
♪♪
-He'll make an excellent puppet.
There's Ward Cleaver.
-What do you think
he's gonna do with that?
♪♪
"Mind if I cut in?"
-"Here's Johnny."
-"Wendy, I'm home."
♪♪
-"Pretty lady!"
"Norman, I told you not
to bother the guests."
-Alan! Alan!
Oh, Alan!
-Oh, my.
-Alan!
Alan, come quickly!
Alan, please!
Alan!
Alan, come quickly!
-Aah!
[Gunshot]
-"And that's for killing
the fat guy."
-Whoa, carries a pistol
in his pajamas.
-What do you think
that pocket's for?
Kleenex?
-Well, look at this.
-What?
-Hans, bring the light closer.
-"Lower, lower, lower."
-Put that on the floor.
-"Even lower."
-See the way his flesh
reflects the light?
-"Pretty."
-Almost as though
it was crystallized.
Like meat
that's been deep frozen.
-I still don't understand
how such --
-Aah!
-Wow.
Unfortunate skin.
-Did we have to see that?
-Alan!
The observatory's just been on.
That cloud's moving again.
-Well, we haven't seen
the monster yet.
It's good to see something.
-It's coming.
-You're wasting your time.
That phone is dead.
The wires have been cut.
We've got to get up
to the observatory.
-But we must --
-You heard what
the professor said,
That place is built like a fort.
If we're gonna have any direct
contact with these things,
at least we'll have
some kind of a chance up there.
-It's insane!
We should try to get out!
To the valley!
-The road is blocked!
The cloud stretches
right across.
-"Now go out and do
something irrational."
-Yes, yes, you --
you go on the next cable car
with the girls.
-"Hey, dudes."
-You've got everyone?
Everyone.
Have 12 left.
One car's already gone up,
and the other one
will be down in 10 minutes.
[Engine revving]
-Who is that?
-"Hey."
-Hans!
"Hey, Hans, get some ice!"
-"Poor fool."
-All right, everybody,
let's get up to the cable car
as quickly as we can.
We haven't got very much time.
-"Oh, really?
I thought we'd just hang around
for an hour or two."
-You got everything?
-Uh-oh.
-What about Anne?-I bet they'll be back for that.
-...the cloud.
-I didn't know they got cable.
-Both channels.
♪♪
-"If we only had a ball --
a small, rubber ball --
then we'd be fine."
-"Wait.
I think I know where
we can find one."
-Professor, are you sure
we're doing the right thing
coming up to your observatory?
-Right or wrong, I don't know.
What I do know is, it's wrong
to stay down in the village.
Up there, we stand some chance,
at least.
-Professor, look,
on the lower slope --
the cloud, moving faster.
-I hope they see it down there.
-The operator says
that it's five minutes now.
-Good.
-Alan.
The cloud's moving
pretty fast now.
♪♪
-Please, folks, I'd like for youall to be ready to load
in the car
as soon as it gets down.
We haven't got
a second to spare.
-Why don't you just spew out
more obvious facts?
-I wish we could see
into that cloud.
At least we'd know
what we're dealing with.
-Well, we'll know soon enough.
-Wow, is that tastelessly done.
It's such a mishmash of styles.
-Kind of garish all around.
-Who decorated this joint?
-Someone with a really
big butt sat there.
♪♪
-Is that the crawling eye, Joel?
-No, that's the little ball.
-Oh.
♪♪
-See, now this is where
your weatherizing
would really pay off.
They're probably losing up to70% of their heat out that door.
-Seems to have stopped
at the hotel.
-Yeah, well, as long as it staysthere, we're all right.
Least that cloud lets us see
where it moves.
Let's get aboard as quickly
as possible, please.
That's it.
Hurry along.
Please, ma'am.
Please.
-My kid.
Where's my kid?
-Of course, the child!
-If that cloud starts to move
this way
before I get back,
take the car up.
Do you understand?
-What about you?
-Do as you're told!
-Too late.
-Whoa!
Holy -- What the --
Geez!
I'm on the edge of my seat.
-He thinks that ball's
one of his pupils.
-Ha ha.
-Oh, sorry, couldn't resist.
-Oh, stop it.
You're killing me.
Ooh, look at that
milky discharge.
I think he has conjunctivitis.
[Child wailing]
-"Now look here, you!"
"Give you a trim."
-Hey, wait!
What about the ball?
[Speaking German]
-Tell her that Mister --
-"Hey."
-Get in the cable car.
-"Tickets.
Everyone?"
-"I don't need one."
-Forrest Tucker.
Oh, look, it feel off
its fabric-softener box.
-Now they got to go back
for the bear.
-We'd better get out of here.
-"I'm out of here."
-That was a close shave.
-Well, we're not through yet.
[Whirring]
-Oh, Joel, it was so horrifying!
-Yeah? Really?
You think so?
-So ugly, so hideous!
-Uh, yeah, that was some eye,
wasn't it?
-No, not the eye.
We're talking about
Forrest Tucker.
-Oh, yeah, all that Vitalis,
those prop glasses,
and those heavy...
dramatic...
pauses.
I'm drained.
-No, you guys.
No, you got it wrong.
You see, the eye is what's
horrible about this movie.
Think about it.
Otherwise,
it would've been called
"The Crawling Forrest Tucker."
-I guess.
Joel, what's so scary
about a big eye, anyway?
-Oh, I see.
Well, it's another
human-being thing.
You know, anytime
we're confronted with some,
uh, appendage of ours
that's disconnected
and free-roaming, rogue,
you know, genetically bloated
to 10 times its normal size,
we're automatically scared.
-Especially if they
run in packs.
-I know what you mean.
Once, I got hassled by a pack ofreally tough pituitary glands.
And you know
how immature they can be.
-I still don't see why
it's so scary.
You could just walk up to it
and throw salt at it.
-Or just a squeeze
of lemon juice.
-Right, I know.
It's kind of a plot hole,
but let's kind of look it over.
You see, these --
Okay, these giant eyes
come from a world that's
designed for them, you know?
It's completely compatible.
Like, their highways are made
out of Nerf, and, uh --
and they don't have to
take shop classes.
-And they only use baby shampoo?-Right.
Right, exactly.
So, anyway, they come down
from this planet,
and they decide to land
on a mountain peak.
-Which is really stupid,
'cause as we all know,
a giant sharp point
is a giant eye's natural enemy.
-Bingo.
So, anyway, they come down,
and they fouled up
their atmosphere somehow.
I don't know.
It's hay fever season
or something.
And they figure they'd come downto Earth,
we'll have our first
frost already done with.
So, they come down,
and they have no concept
of anything at all,
like wearing safety glasses
or protective eyewear
of any kind.
-Joel, I think we've already
spent more time
examining this plot
than the writers ever did.
-Now here's something
you'll really like.
[Theme music playing]
-This is the last time.
-Put me down.
[Whirring]
-As a fog emerges
over Trollenberg,
our young group escapes.
-Looks like everything's
free and clear now.
Nothing to do but...
-Remember that telephone wire
to the hut?
-...get up the rope.
-Sit back and relax.
Enjoy the ride.
Uh-oh.
Maybe we spoke too soon.
-Oh, now they're gonna have
to wait all day
for that cable guy to show up.
-This contraption operate
in extreme cold?
-We've worked the cable car
in 30-below.
-Colder than that?
-Colder than a winch.
-Tell scary stories.
-Oh, my.
-The cable!
It will snap!
-"Am I gonna have time to changemy pants when I get there?"
-Oh, funny.
Good one.
Tell them all about
the giant eye, Forrest.
-All right, look, everybody out.
That's it.
-We're leaving the villagers
out here, sir.
It's shut and safe,
and they won't get in the way.
-The radio still working?
-We tested it about
15 minutes ago.
-Alan, come here.
Alan, we're in big trouble.
-What now?
-The cloud is splitting up.
-Splitting up?
-There are four of them now
and all moving this way.
-Four eyes.
-How long before they get here?
-An hour maybe.
-Well, that gives us an hour
to decide what we're gonna do.
Better check that radio again.
-You're going to signal
the authorities?
-And tell them what?
What do you use
against these things?
-High explosives.
-Bombs?
The time the plane gets here,
those things will be
all over us.
How do they drop
their bombs then?
-Set's still working okay, sir,
-Good.
Let me see that thing again.
-There's someone knockingat the outside door, Herr Wilde.
-It's Bob Hope.
-"Hey, there.
Join me this week with Brooke
Shields and Erik Estrada.
-He's doing a walk-on
in this movie.
-Is that a good Bob Hope, Joel?
-Well, we don't make up
our minds pretty soon,
they'll be made up for us.
-What does he mean by that?
-What's the matter?
What happened?
-He looks plastered.
-It walked straight
across the room.
I turned the car and came back.
-You all right?
-"Couldn't get it out
of first, huh?"
-Yes, I'm all right, thank you.
It is so hot in here.
-Uh-oh.
-Stay here with
the others, Hans.
You'll be all right soon.
-And don't breathe on anybody.
♪♪
-"What is it, my breath?"
-The Certs encounter.
-♪ Young love, first love
-♪ Wah wah, whoo
-Anne, where are you going?
-I'm just going to
sit down in the office.
-All right.
But how can Anne help?
She doesn't know anything.
-Obviously.
-We don't know for sure
that she can, but, Sarah,
we've got to try something.
Obviously, she has some kind
of contact with these things...
-Obviously.-...whether she knows it or not.
I thought perhaps with you
controlling her thinking, we --
well, we might be able
to learn something
about what we're dealing with.
-I suppose we could try.
-Maybe that's what those eyes
want is contacts.
-It's going down all the time.
-It's 45 below.
-Still dropping.It's a cloud location, isn't it?
-There is a cloud there, yes.
-Wait a minute.
Say it's cold they need.
They live in cold.
Remember the phone wires
at the hut?
-"They're cold."
-And Brett claimed of being hot
after he was infected.
-He was cold.
-He complained of things --
-Suppose they were --
-Because they were cold.
-Hans, what about him?
-He arrived a few moments ago.
-He's cool.
-Said he changed his mind
about trying to escape.
He complained --
-Where is he?
-Out in the corridor.
-He's cold.
-Hans is on the fritz.
-Where's Hans?
-"He had a cold."
-I just saw him a minute ago.
-He came in here.
Anne!
-"Get your hands off me!"
-"Hey, one at a time,
one at a time."
-"No Leap Frog, come on."
-Quit roughhousing.
-Everyone'll get a chance.
-Wait, my dear, please.
-Aah! Aah!
-"Take it back! Take it back,
what you said about my eye!"
-"Uncle!
Uncle!"
"Tickle machine!
Tickle machine!"
-Aah!
-Hans across the letter opener.
-He's washed his "Hans" of that.
-Poor devil.
-"Wait'll I get my
'Hans' on you."
-Anne!
-She'll be all right, I think.
-Well, better take care of him.
-I think you already did.
-"Are you hurting?"
-"Bring any fish?"
-He'll get over it.
-How thick are these walls?
-I don't know.
2, 3 feet maybe?
-Fireproof?
-Well, yes, they're
reinforced concrete against
the avalanche.
-Good. Hugo, get on the radio,
the United Nations in Bern.
I want to talk
to Colonel Spellman.
-Yowza.
-Now that Anne can't
help us anymore,
there's only one thing left.
-What's that?
-What I said before.
Every time we've come up
against these things,
there has been this
intense cold, remember?
You said that Brett looked like
he'd been in the deep freeze.
Heat.
That's what we've got to use.
I'm gonna ask
for a bombing raid.
-You said that was impossible.
-Fire bombs --
that's our answer.
-Through to Bern, Mr Brooks.
-"Fire bomb?
You just hired him."
-...and all the jars
and bottles you got.
-"Give me six bags of onions
and a giant eye chart."
♪♪
It's getting creepy.
Ah, it's cold.
-Give him a giant scissors.
Maybe he'll put himself out.
-Well, all eyes are
on the observatory now.
-Was there a sequel
to this movie?
-Yes, "The Eye-ger Sanction."
-Oh, oh...
-Good one.
-I...
-Starring Burl Eyes.
-Right.
I mean, I don't get this.
What's a giant eye
gonna do to you, anyway?
Like, pick you up
and wink you to death?
-It's just not gonna happen.
It's not practical.
-We're all eyewitnesses, though.
-Mine eyes have seen the "gory."
-Ooh, you did it again.
-Ooh.
-Kind of, uh... Ah, well.
-Pretty highbrow.
-I think a bit more in that one.
-That's the way I like them.
-Herr Klein.
-Very dry fire bomb.
-Make sure you get that rag
stuffed in there tight
so the petrol won't leak.
-"Yep. Got it."
-Shaken, not stirred.
-Would have your attention,
please.
I don't want anyone to leave
this corridor unless I say so.
Understood?
-"What if we have to go?"
-...as many of these ready
as you can, and...
-"Hold them."
-...they're dangerous.
-And I can tell you
that help's on its way.
-"I can't guarantee
you'll survive."
-Well, they seemed to buy it.
-Alan.
-Yeah?
-How are we gonna use
these bombs of yours?
-They'll light the rags
and throw them
at those things in the cloud.
-"Then you run.
Is that so complicated?"
-Look at this.
-♪ Eye yi, yi yi
-Wow. Now I know how it feels to
be in a microscope.
-Cute little things,
aren't they?
-Yeah.
I'm gonna throw a bomb
at that one.
You watch on the screen,
see what happens.
-One of your movies, Forrest?
-Would y'all go up far
into the corridor, please?
Except you -- you come with me.
-"Huh?
Why me?"
-I want you to slam this door
behind me and wait for me
to knock to come back in.
If I don't knock,
don't open it, right?
-"R-Right.
Okay.
So, if you knock, uh,
I open it."
-All right.
-"All right, okay.
Now, if you don't knock --
Wait, wait!
Let me get a piece of paper!
Darn."
[High-pitched whine]
-♪ Shave and a haircut
-"Who is it?
Oh, it's you."
-Get me a couple more
of those bottles.
-I saw it on the screen.
-Those things can really move.
We've either got to get a directhit or surround them with
so much flame
they can't get out.
-Let me try one.
-Okay, but it's not that fun.
Go ahead.
-Remember the secret knock.
-"What knock?"
-Wait, they are big.
[High-pitched whine]
-Uh-oh.
♪♪
-Alan, there's one on the roof!
-You've got a now lash on life.
-"But he didn't knock yet.
Hey, same knock deal?"
♪♪
"Rats, I missed."
-Yeah.
-Saved him in the blink
of an eye.
-Nice stunt, though.
♪♪
-Oh, rugged.
-Thanks.
You all right?
-"I feel so dirty."
-Thanks, Alan.
Now what?
-I don't know.
Can't go out that door again,
that's for sure.
It's the only way in or out
of this observatory.
I've checked.
-"Maybe we should panic."
-"Maybe we should go
to a commercial."
-"We could take a short break
for the tedium."
-"Did you guys get enough eyes?
You seen enough
horrible eyes yet?
Yeah?"
-"Hmm, yeah.
My eyes are burning."
[Theme music playing]
-What are they doing now?
-Can't tell anymore.
They block out the cameras.
You see?
-Yeah.
-It's all teared up.
-♪ Here I come to save the day
-Jolly Roger to observatory.
Jolly Roger to observatory.
Receiving you loud and clear.
ETA in five minutes.
-"No need to come
to the party anymore.
All the cool people are dead."
-ETA in about five minutes.
-Good.
Tell him to make a straight run
over the observatory
and drop his bombs on the roof.
Hope he knows what he's doing.
-I hope you know
what you're doing.
-"How's she doing?"
-No change?
-"No change, couple of bills,
went through her purse,
found my comb."
♪♪
That eye is lashing
out at society.
-Hello, observatory, I'm...
-Taking quite a browbeating
on these puns.
-Tell him to bomb the cloud.
-Hello, Jolly Roger --
drop first streak
across observatory and cloud.
Understand?
Bomb the cloud, as well.
Over.
-Look, observatory, sounds crazyto me bombing a cloud.
-Do as you're told, over!
-Yes, sir.
Out.
-Whoever cast this movie
had an eye for talent.
-Okay, that's it. Stop it.
-Sorry.
-Joel's getting really eye-rate.
-Thanks, you guys.
Thanks for everything.
-I can see the problem.
-We'll know soon enough.
♪♪
-I spy with my little eye...
-You hypocrite.
[Chuckles]
-...something that sounds
like a gigantic eye!
Long, longer, longest.
Beautiful eyelashes that
grab people and strangle them.
-That is one "eyeful" tower.
Oh!
-We're hurtin'.
-Hurts, doesn't it?
Keep in mind, you programmed me.
-It's the last time I give you
free will, though.
That's it after today.
-Whoa!
-That'll make the mascara run.
-We'll try a high-level
attack first.
Here we go.
-"I feel the need --
the need for speed."
[Jet engine roaring]
-Or an antidepressant.
-Tora, tora, tora!
♪♪
-Steady. Steady.
Device set to off.
Steady.
Bombs away.
-And bomb the ship Arizona!
-Where's Major Carr?
-So that's what it sounds like
when eyes cry.
-And we're an eyewitness.
-I beat you to that one.
[Chuckles]
-Guess kind of eye-witless.
I blame myself.
-Come on, quiet.
There's a lot of destruction we
should be paying attention to.
-Eye-yi-yi.
[Jet engine roars,
bombs exploding]
-I'd like to shake tentacles
with any eye that could last
through that, that's for sure.
-Looks like a bunch of
overcooked fried eggs.
-Bet it smells good.
-I bet they don't go out for
breakfast after this battle,
that's for sure.
♪♪
-Kingsford eyeballs --
edges light quick, burn clean.
[Joel chuckles]
-I like mine mesquite grilled.
He tips his wingsas he flies off into the sunset.
♪♪
-Ookie.
[Imitates creaking]
-There's that mountain.
-Oh, Wilde, tell the villagers
they can go down the mountain
anytime they'd like.
-"And tell the villagers
to wear boots."
-How about a breath
of fresh air?
-I don't think outside
is the place
to get some fresh air right now.
-Well, Sarah, doesn't look
as though
you'll have to worry
about her any longer.
-No, it doesn't.
Cigarette?
-Yes, it is.
-Well, Alan, for the first time
in weeks,
the Trollenberg
is free from clouds.
-Yes, and let's hope
it stays that way.
-♪ I can see clearly now
The rain is gone ♪
♪ I can see all obstacles
in my way ♪
♪♪
[Whirring]
-All right, that's the end
of the movie, everybody.
And you know what that means.
-Yay!
-RAM chips and dip.
-And afterwards,
a borium power flush.
-Boo!
-I'm just kidding.
-Yay!
-Okay.
Now, you know how it works.
No, no, just wait your turn.
You'll get a RAM chip.
Okay, Crow, you go first.
Now tell me a good thing about
the movie and the bad thing,
and you get your RAM chip.
Good thing?
-Uh, the good thing was,
it wasn't longer.
-Okay.
And the bad thing?
-It was this long.
-Okay, there's your
RAM chip, pally.
-Yay!
-Open up. There you go.
All right.
-RAM chip now.
-Okay, no, no.
Wait on your RAM chip, Gypsy.
Okay, Tom Servo.
-All right, okay, let's see.
The good thing was, is that
we didn't have to watch them
clean up the vitreous humor all
over from the eyes exploding.
Imagine, you sign up that day
for Kelly Temps --
Trollenberg office, of course --
they give you a leaky bucket
and a turkey baster,
send you up the mountain,
now you're on cleanup crew.
-And the bad thing?
-Well, the bad thing was, uh...
the movie?
It was ambitious,
but it lacked vision.
-Well, hindsight is 20/20.
-Terrific.
Okay, well, here's your
RAM chip, pal.
-Thank you!
-Okay, okay,
it's time
for your RAM chip, Gypsy.
All you got to do
is answer the questions,
and you get the RAM chips, okay?
All right, tell me a good thing
about the movie.
-Can I have a RAM chip, Joel?
-Well, tell me a bad thing
about the movie, Gypsy.
Oh, you don't know?
Okay, okay.
Uh, just answer
this one question,
I'll give you RAM chips, okay?
What's 2 plus 2?
-Richard Basehart?
-Oh, good one, okay.
There you go.
All right, yeah.
Okay, well, that's the end
of the experiment, you guys.
Hope you're happy.
-Oh, I'm happy.
Are you happy?
Here, file this.
[Both laugh]
Well, we'll see you next time,
Joely-Poely Puddin'-n-Pie!
♪♪